

Philson Danniel Raj M

Technical Lead

Phone: 9976755595,8072203501

Address: 2/332 T, R.S.Nagar, Chinniyampalayam,

Coimbatore-641062

Email: Philsoncedric28@gmail.com

Dot Net Developer with 8.2 years of experience in developing web applications. Adept in handling the requirements of application and discussing requirements with clients, writing code, working with business analysts, implementing best development practices, and solving design problems.

EXPERIENCE

Orion Business Innovation

August 2019 - Present

Technical Lead

- Worked as Software Developer in building web-applications.
- Responsible for building modules based on the client requirement.
- Leading the team towards the sprint-goals

Daemon Software and Services

June 2016 - July 2019

Associate Consultant

- Worked as a Team Player in building large web applications.
- Responsible as a Full stack Developer in building modules in web application.
- Worked as a Team-Lead in building applications.

EDUCATION

INFO Institute of Engineering

June 2012 - April 2016

Bachelor of Engineering(ECE)

GRG Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Coimbatore

June 2011 - April 2012

12 Grade

St.Joseph's Matriculation School

June 2009 - April 2010

10 Grade

SKILLS

Asp.Net Framework,ASP.Net Core
Azure Cloud services
Azure Devops
MVC Architecture
ADO.NET and Entity Framework
AngularJs,Angular (6-14)
Javascript
JQuery

C#, WCF Services, Rest Api HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3 MSSQL,MySQL

PROJECTS

OTTP(Tax Based Project)

Sep 2022 - till Date

OTTP is service-based project build for purpose of tax filing of clients. It includes K1/K2/K3 form filing of clients. This application handles complex calculation and import/export of excel file into forms.

Technologies: Angular 13, Dot net core 3.1, Azure sql database, Microservices, docker, Aks

Role: Developer, Technical Lead

Research and Development(Tax based Project)

Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

R&D is service-based project build for tax compliance of clients. This Project is used to file tax and approve surveys for managing funds to clients.

Technologies : Angular 13,Dot net core 3.1,Azure sql database, Microservices, Docker and Azure kubernetes

Role: Technical Lead

Raptor Mar 2020 - Mar 2022

Raptor is a service-based project built for tax compliance of the clients. This application is used to track tax essentials of the client.

Technology: Angular 7, Kendo-UI,Dot Net Core,MSSQL

Role: Developer

OVMS - Orion Visitor Management System

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

OVMS is an web-based application used to track the visitors and material entering into the office. This application is used by the admin of an office to track in and out happenings from remote locations.

Technology: Angular 9, Angular material, Angular FLex-Layout

Role: Front-End Team Lead, Developer

BIGS- Background Information Gateway

Sep 2019 to Dec 2019

BIGS is a web-based application used for the background verification of the players of a team. It is a sports project. It consists of different roles to manage the activities inside the application.

Technology: Angular 7, Angular material, Flex Layout

Role: Front-end Team Lead, Developer

VIPTIX

April 2019 to Sep 2019

VIPTIX is a web application used to book tickets for the game. This application is used by the employees of the organisation to book the tickets for match for the year. It is mainly used by organisation which approves and allocates the seats for the employees for the respective matches.

Technology: AngularJs, AngularJs material design

Role: Front-end Developer

Employee Portal

February 2019 to March 2019

A web application which helps to organize entire activities of a company such as Employee details,Project Information, Daily tasks and leaves

Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder

Technology: Angular 7, Web api(Dapper), MSSQL

Role : Team-Lead,Developer

KLIP (Learning Management System)

February 2017 to March 2019

A learning management system (LMS) is a software application for the

administration, documentation, tracking, reporting and delivery of educational courses or training programs. They help the instructor deliver material to the students, administer tests and other assignments, track student progress, and manage record-keeping. LMS support a range of uses, from supporting classes that meet in physical classrooms to acting as a platform for fully online courses, as well as several hybrid forms, such as blended learning and flipped classrooms.

Technology: C#.net, AngularJS, MVC n-tier Technology, WCF, MS SQL Server 2014

Role: Developer, UI designer

E-remit February 2017 to May 2017

E-Remit is a remittance project used to make money transaction between individuals using a product. It consists of stack holders like back end user and customer.

Power and energy management

March 2018 to July 2018

Power and energy management is to monitor, analyze and control the power consumption. The Power supply for the individual unit (Room-Floor-Block) can be switched on/off remotely using IOT Application. The data is collected through IOT device and sent to the centralized server where the reports can be generated to know the consumption pattern of each room/units and floor.

Technology Used: Rest Api(Dapper), MySQL

Role: Developer

Resource Management Project

September 2016 to Jan 2017

A web application which helps to organize entire activities of a company such as employee details, availability, project details.

Technology Used: C#.net, Angular JS, MS SQL Server 2014

Role: Developer, UI designer

Energy Matrix – Reconciliation Application and Netting Service

July 2016 to September 2016

Energy Matrix – Reconciliation Application and Netting Service is a hosted web enabled, smart device capable application, written for use on smart devices and computers with web/internet capabilities that will facilitate ticket reconciliation,netting and management components of the midstream to upstream oil and gas production process.

Technology Used: Asp.net, MSSQL Server 2014

Role: Support Developer

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 28/11/1994

Present Address : 2/332 T, R.S.Nagar, Chinniyampalayam, Coimbatore-641062

Email: philsoncedric28@gmail.com

Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder